This story is fiction. The names of people,
places and groups are imaginary.
Obey traffic rules and drive safely.
Initial
Raise up your hands　高く [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands high.
(Everybody now raise your hands)
Take hold, there's a brand new tomorrow.
掴め　Brand new tomorrow [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
風の中で　自分を知る　ずっと最高のDreamだろう
It's a beautiful eternal dream...
...where you learn about yourself.
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh raise up you can't stop
Oh, raise up your hands now.
If you think you're lucky just to be alive go for the highest stake in the gamble.
生きてるだけで何やろうかな
Gamble on　迫る鼓動にテンバリ
同じMission　同じ一生
Same mission creates similar lives.
But your passion for your dream will make a difference.
どんだけ夢熱いかが勝負だろ
You can never use the escalator.
Escalator　無しの永遠
But you can build up your strength, yeah yeah.
足腰鍛え　Let's begin yeah
You must eventually climb the stairs.
どうせのぼる階段
心こっちにCustomizeしちゃえばいい
Customize them the way you like.
Intense days go by.
削られて　過ぎる毎日[But you know]
Intense days go by. (But you know?)
攻めがいのあるGameと　笑い飛ばして
Just laugh it off, 'cause it's a game worth competing.
Let's see how fast you can do it
Let's see how fast you can do it.
Raise up your hands　ずっと [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands forever.
(Everybody now raise your hands up)
Run, sleepless challenger.
走れ　Sleepless challenger [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
今に生きる　理由を探す
It's a quest of the never-ending dream...
...where you now search for the reason to live.
夢尽きないQuest
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
いいよな　箱根の霧は
Hakone's fog is nice.
薄汚れた現実を全てかき消してくれる
It hides the dirty side of reality.
こうして佇んでいれば
When I stand still like this, there's
nothing other than absolute silence...
そこにあるのは絶対的な静寂　そして圧倒的な孤独だ
...and overwhelming loneliness.
涅槃とはこんなところかもしれないな　香織
This is the state of nirvana, right, Kaori ?
お前を失ってから
Ever since I lost you, I feel like
I've been standing in the fog.
俺はいつも霧の中に佇んでいるようなものだ
ここで俺は涼介と命の遣り取りをする
I'm going to have a race against
Ryosuke where we both bet our lives.
俺たち二人のうちどちらかを
I'll send one of us to your side.
お前の傍に送ってやるよ
選ぶのはお前だ
So make a choice.
今度こそ本音で選らんだぜ　香織
This time, follow your heart, Kaori.
久しぶりだな　涼介
Long time no see, Ryosuke.
You look a little neater, huh ?
少しチャラくなったか
お久しぶりです　北条凛　先輩
It's been a while, Hojo Rin.
Senpai.
話は聞いたよ
I've heard the story.
I called Ryosuke's cell,
but it seems to be turned off.
涼介の携帯に掛けてみたけど
電源がはいてなくて
メッセージを残したけど返て来ないし
I left a message,
but I haven't heard back.
大学の研究室にもいないって
I've been told that he's not
in the college lab either.
涼介がFCを密かに改造していたとすれば
If Ryosuke secretly modified his FC,
I'm sure he must have a reason for it.
絶対何か目的があるはずだ
FCのチューニングやメンテンナンスをずっと手がけてきたのは松本だからさ
Matsumoto is the one who's been
tuning and maintaining the FC...
...so I've tried calling him to find
out if he knows something, but...
松本なら何か知ってるんじゃないかと思って電話してるんだが
こっちも連絡取れない
...I can't reach him either.
二人揃って行方不明だなんて
Something is definitely not
right with both of them missing.
どう考えても引っかかるよ
そういう事なら
If that's the case, I'll just ignore this.
この件は　あえて忘れる
Huh ?
I mean, for the time being it's
pointless for us to get upset over this.
ここで俺たちがジタバタしてるも始まらないって事だ
そうはいかないだろう　心配じゃないのか
How could you not be ?
Aren't you worried ?
兄貴が動くからには相応の理由がある
My brother must have a
significant reason for doing this...
俺達に黙って　単独で行動するのにもな
...including going solo behind our back.
昔からそうなんだ　史浩なら分かるだろう
He's always been been like this.
You know that, don't you ?
He always makes the right choice.
兄貴のやることに間違いはない
必ず何事も無かったのようにシレッと帰ってくる
He'll come back and feign
ignorance as if nothing happened.
信じて待っていればいいんだ
Just have faith in him and wait.
There's no point in worrying.
心配なんてしなくていい
みんな普段どおりのことをやろう
Let's just act like we normally do.
What we should be doing now
is preparing for the final battle.
今俺達がやるべき事は
最終戦に向けての準備だろ
兄貴がこの場にいたら絶対にそういうはずだ
That's what my brother
would say if he were here.
There's no need to worry
about a remote possibility.
もしもの事なんてありえない
兄貴は日本一クレバーな公道ランナーだってことを
He's Japan's most ingenious street racer.
Don't forget that.
忘れるなって
Grim Reaper
涼介さん
Ryosuke...
俺はここで待ってます
I'll be waiting here, so please
pick me up when you're done.
終わったら拾いに来て下さい
俺は涼介さんの助手席で群馬に帰る予定ですから
I plan to return to Gunma
in your car's passenger seat.
それ以外の手段で帰るつもりはないです
I haven't thought about any other way.
二日でも三日でもここで待ってます
Even if it takes several days, I'll be waiting...
例え雨を降っても　例え土砂降りの雨になっても
Even if it rains, to the point where I get soaked...
つまり　貴方が戻らなければ
In other words, if you
don't return, I'll die here.
俺もこの場所でのたれ死ぬ予定です
お前ならやり兼ねないな
I can really see you doing that.
必ず戻る
I'll return no matter what.
ありがとう
Thank you.
約束ですよ　涼介さん
It's a promise, Ryosuke.
Please come back safely.
無事に戻ってきてください
白いFC
A white FC ?
そうなんだよ
Yeah.
A guy saw it when he was
visiting Akagi the other day.
この間　赤城の方へ行った奴が見たって
それって　高橋涼介が観瀑したってことか
Do you mean Takahashi
Ryosuke is making a comeback ?
そんなはずないっすよ
There's no way.
コアなファンが真似してるだけじゃないっすか
It's probably a copy by a hardcore fan.
なら　まだいいけど
That could be the case.
ほら　この前みたいに偽物が現れたとか
Remember those impersonators the other day ?
それはないだろう
That's not likely.
赤城は高橋涼介の地元なんだから
Akagi is Takahashi Ryosuke's home ground.
偽物なんてすぐにバレるよ
Any impersonator would
get caught immediately.
そうっすよね
He's right.
Hey, did Takumi say anything ?
なぁ　拓海は何も言ってなかったのか
何も聞いてないっすけど
Not a thing.
I'd better call him.
ちょっと電話してみます
あいつこんまえみたいに親友差し置いてしかとしたら
If he ignores his best friend like he did the other day, I'll chew him out.
こんどこそ徹底的に取っちめてやる
涼介さんが
Ryosuke did ?
いや　そんな話全然聞いてないよ
No, I don't know anything about it.
うん　単に似た車だったんじゃないかな
Maybe it's just a look-alike.
Okay, bye.
うん　じゃ
どうしたの　また偽物騒ぎ
What's wrong ?
Another impersonator ?
あっ　いいや　別にそこまでは言ってないと思うよ
Um, no, I don't think it's that serious.
でも今になって見れば　あの偽物に感謝しなくちゃね
But come to think of it, we have
to thank those impersonators.
After all, I met you because of them.
だって　あの二人のおかげで
こうして拓海君に出会えたんだもの
そうだな
I guess so.
ね　拓海くん　また二人でどうか行こうよ
Hey, Takumi, why don't we go
somewhere together again ?
海は行ったから　今度は山かな
We've been to the beach,
so how about the mountains ?
危険過ぎる
This is way too risky.
I've never seen such a high-speed
downhill stage like this anywhere.
これほどの超高速ダウンヒルステージは
他では見たことがない
コースを知っている地元を相手に
It's really disadvantageous to be in
the lead position against a local.
先行はあまりにも不利だ
ブランクがある上に
He hasn't had time to become familiar
with the renewed FC after his hiatus.
リニューアルしたFCに対応するだけの時間も無かった
けど　ここまで来たらもう信じるしかない
But all I can do now is believe in the super driving
sense from his days as Akagi's White Comet.
赤城の白い彗星と呼ばれていた頃の
冴え渡っていたドライビングセンスを　涼介さん
Ryosuke...
三年前かな
Three years ago...
Eh ?
...I fell in love with someone.
俺はある人を好きになったんだ
その人は大学の一年先輩で
She was my senior by one year at college,
and a type of person I hadn't met before.
それまではあまり出会ったことはないタイプの人だった
自由奔放で　大人と子供が同居していて
Free-spirited, half childish, half mature.
強いくせにもろい　矛盾だらけの人だったよ
Sometimes strong-willed, but sometimes weak, a person with lots of contradictions.
でも俺は　そんな所に引かれたのかもな
But that's probably why I was attracted to her.
自分でもコントロール出来ないくらい
I lost my head over her to the
extent that I couldn't control myself.
のぼせ上がっていたんだ
意外かもな　俺のそんな所は
It's out of character for me, I guess.
I haven't told anyone about this, but can
you bear with my little story, Matsumoto ?
この事は　今まで誰にも話した事は無かったんだけど
少しだけ聞いてもらえるか　松本
旋回能力は互角か
Cornering potential is equal, but my
car has significantly greater power.
パワーは明らかにこっちが上だ
制動に関しては　軽い分向こうに利がある
As for braking, his car has the
advantage because of the lighter weight.
終盤に行けば行くほどそれは顕著なものになっていくだろう
It will become more apparent
toward the end of the battle.
だが　俺にとっては好都合だ
But that works fine for me.
止まれないなら　不可抗力としてぶつけるだけのこと
If I can't stop, I won't be able to
avoid slamming my car into his.
勝負は一本　見事に逃げきれれば　お前の勝ちだ
There will only be one round.
If you manage to get away, you win.
逃がさないだな
But I won't let you.
涼介君
Ryosuke...
自分が何のために生まれてきたのか
Why do you think you were born ?
考えたこと有る　涼介君
Have you ever thought about it, Ryosuke ?
また出た　香織さんの禅問答が
There you go again.
Another philosophical question.
はぐらかなさないで答えてみなさいよ
Don't dodge my question, try to answer it.
自分が本当にやりたいってことってなんなの
What do you really want to do ?
親の跡を継ぐことがホントにしたいこと
Do you really want to succeed your parents ?
君は本当に医者何かに成りたくてうちの大学にいるの
Are you attending college because
you actually want to become a doctor ?
そんなのは恵まれてるとは言えないよ
You can't be happy with that.
寧ろ不幸よ　選択の自由のない
It's rather sad if you can't
choose what to do with your life.
つまんない人生
痛いとこ着くね　香織さん
You're hitting a sore spot, Kaori.
君の幸せってなに
What makes you happy ?
本当の幸せってなに
What makes you truly happy ?
Don't you have a dream ?
夢はないの
涼介君の夢ってなに
What is your dream, Ryosuke ?
どうだ
Any news ?
確認しました　死神のR３２です
I spotted the Grim Reaper's R32.
It'll pass by your location,
chasing a white car at high speed.
白い車を追って　猛スピードでもうすぐそこを通過します
くれぐれも気をつけてください　池田さん
Please be very careful, Ikeda.
了解
Got it.
ついに捕捉したぜ　死神
I've finally got you, Grim Reaper.
スパイラルは箱根の自警団的役割を自負しているチームだ
Team Spiral is proud to be the
neighborhood watch of Hakone.
峠のルールを壊す存在には断じて許さん
We won't forgive anyone who breaks
the rules of the mountain pass.
あんたの狼藉も今日限りだ
Your insolence ends today.
それにしても　まえを行く白いFCは何者だ
Anyway, who's driving that white FC ?
あの死神を相手に先行のポジションとはまた豪胆だ
How reckless of you to take the lead
position against the Grim Reaper.
ただ者ではない　まさか
He must have nerves of steel.
Could that be...
...him ?!
あの男か
涼介君　君に話してないことが有るんだ
Ryosuke, there's something I haven't told you yet.
私ね　親が決めた婚約者がいるの
I have a fiancé chosen by my parents.
後何年かしたらその人と結婚するんだよ
I'll have to marry him in a few years.
つまんないジョックだよね　香織さん
That's a bad joke, Kaori.
Do you really want to
follow your parents' wishes ?
親の意思に従うことが　ホントに貴方のしたいことなの
そんなの全然貴方らしくないけど
That's not like you at all.
君はホントの私を知らないだけ
You just don't know the true me.
なら　これから知ればいい
Then I'll begin to discover it from now on.
I'm not going to give you up.
俺は　香織さんを諦めるつもりはないから
だめよ
No...
諦めて
Please give up.
なにが　香織さんを泣かすの
Why are you crying ?
俺は　なにがあっても　香織さんを守るよ
I'll protect you no matter what.
どうした涼介
What's wrong, Ryosuke ?
コーナーの進入にわずかだが迷いが見えるぜ
I see a slight hesitation in your corner entries.
超高速ステージが怖いか
Are you scared of this
super high-speed stage ?
Or is it because of your hiatus ?
それともブランクのせいか
甘いぜ涼介　寝ぼけてるんなら目を覚ませ
You're so naive, Ryosuke.
If you're spacing out, I'll wake you up.
He did it already.
早速やりやがった
ターンイン直後の安定期に入る直前にあれをやられるのが
Rear wheel drive cars are defenseless against that kind
of push right after the turn-in when the car is unstable.
後輪駆動には一番辛い
死神は確信犯でそこをついてくる
The Grim Reaper did it on purpose.
Please recover.
立ち直ってくれ
うまい　見事だ
Wow, that was incredible.
That's more like it.
That was my way of saying "Hi."
そうでなくちゃな
こんなのはあいさつ代わりだ
コントロールできる　いい仕上がりだ
I can control the car.
It's well tuned, as always, Matsumoto.
さすがだな　松本
これなら行ける
Now I know I can push myself
to the limit without hesitation.
心おきなく　ぎりぎりの領域へ
もう一発　次はきついぜ
Here comes the next one. It'll be harder.
違う　今までと明らかに違う
The Grim Reaper is acting
differently from before.
He's seriously trying to...
死神は本気で
外した
He missed ?!
あの死神が本気で当てに行ってかわされた
The Grim Reaper's serious
attempt to crash was dodged.
なんたるつっこみ
What incredible acceleration.
もう間違いない　あのFCは
There's no more doubt about that FC.
北関東最強と言われた　カリスマの復活
The charismatic driver, who was once
the best in northern Kanto, has returned.
一体なにが
What made him do that ?
涼介
Ryosuke...
なにが起こっているんだ
What's going on ?
死神が変だ　あからさまに殺気を漲らせている
The Grim Reaper is acting strange,
showing true hostile intent.
それを受けるあの男も
The other guy is well aware of it,
but he isn't even trying to escape.
それが分かっていながら離脱しようともしない
これはだたのバトルじゃない
This is no ordinary battle.
It looks like I ran into
an extraordinary situation.
俺はとんでもない場面に出くわしてしまったようだ
さすがだな　涼介
Just like you, Ryosuke.
Your earlier hesitation is gone.
先まであった躊躇が消えた
素晴らしい順応力だ
You've got incredible adaptability.
You're a much better
driver than I expected.
お前は想像以上のドライバーだよ
香織　近くに来て　見ているんだろう
Are you nearby, Kaori, watching us ?
このバトルお前に捧げる
I dedicate this battle to you.
俺は　今夜この場所で死んでも悔いはない
Even if I die here tonight, I won't regret it.
なにも怖くないんだ
I'm not afraid of anything.
ごめんなさい　北条さん
I'm sorry, Hojo.
I can't marry you.
結婚はできません
待ってくれ　それはないぜ
Hold on, that's so abrupt. Tell me why.
訳を言ってくれ　親が決めたからとか
This has nothing to do with
our parents' arrangement.
そういう事じゃないんだ
分かってくれ　香織
Don't you know that I love you
from the bottom of my heart ?
俺はもう心の底からお前が好きだということを
恐ろしいぜ　なんというテンションの高さだ
This is scary.
Their tension is off the scale.
二人の間に割って入る所か
I'm having a hard time keeping up with them,
much less cutting in between them.
ついて行くだけでも苦しい
それにしても高橋涼介
Besides, that Takahashi Ryosuke...
理論派と聞いていたが　それは絶対に違う
I heard he was the logical type, but that's not true.
天才タイプでしかこんな芸当は出来ない
Only a genius could pull off this kind of driving.
地元ではない走り屋がこれほどのペスを作れるのは
It's almost a miracle for a
non-local to maintain this high pace.
ほとんど奇跡だぜ
This course is so unique that even the
locals don't push themselves to the limit...
それほどそこは特別なコースなんだ
地元でも下りを限界まで攻めることはまずしない
命がいくつあっても足りないからな
...because you only have one life.
速い　芸術的なロータリー使いだぜ
So fast.
His handling of the rotary
engine is almost an art.
天才の感覚とクレーバー過ぎる頭脳が両立しているというわけか
So, even being known as the logical type, it's because he
has both the sense of a genius and an all-too-clever mind ?
それが理論派高橋涼介の真実だ
That's the true nature of Takahashi Ryosuke.
だが死神のホントの恐ろしさは
But the Grim Reaper will show his
truly frightening nature up ahead.
これから先が本番なんだ
涼介君
Ryosuke.
君って不思議な人だね
You're a mysterious person.
年下のくせに落ち着いてて
You're younger than me, but more
composed, which irritates me a bit.
それがちょっとシャクに触るけど
But you're always honest,
kind and strong-minded...
いつも誠実で優しくて　心が強い
きっと君は女の子を幸せにするんだろうね
...the type of person who
can make a woman happy.
私でいいの
I'm not sure if I can be the one.
自信ないよ
Maybe I don't deserve your feelings.
君に思われる資格　ないかも
ずっと側にいられたら
I wish I could...
君の側にいられたらいいの
...be by your side forever.
Fujiwara Takumi:
Takahashi Ryosuke:
Hojo Rin:
Kaori:
Ikeda Ryuji:
Matsumoto:
Miki Shinichiro
Koyasu Takehito
Nakamura Yuichi
Endo Aya
Nakai Kazuya
Nishi Rintaro
日の暮れに　変わらない景色
Even when night falls, the scenery remains unchanged.
Takahashi Keisuke:
Iketani Koichiro:
Kenji:
Takeuchi Itsuki:
Fumihiro:
Sakamoto:
Uehara Mika:
Seki Tomokazu
Yao Kazuki
Takagi Wataru
Iwata Mitsuo
Hosoi Hajime
Okano Kosuke
Hayami Saori
振り返る　辿ってきた道
Looking back at the path I've taken.
切なさも　喜びも　消えない痛みも
Sadness, happiness, incurable pains...
Realizing that there are too many to count, as I walk alone.
数えてたら限がないねと独り歩く
A
Central Anime
Production
Translation:
Hiro-kun
Timing:
Todd Perkins
Editing:
Lillian-Hime
Barbara
Todd Perkins
Brain
Dave
Mouse
Steve S.
Namke
Countless number of memorable scenes.
数え切れないほどの残像　ギャンブル生き抜いてきた残党
We lived through the hustle and bustle.
時に戦い　時に解りあい　きれい事ばかりじゃなかった真実
Sometimes we argued, sometimes we understood.
It wasn't always pretty, but I keep the truth to myself...
背負ったまま新たな一歩
...as I take a new step.
あかね雲が街を染める　この行く先をそっと問いかけて見る
Rosy clouds embellish the city.
I quietly ask about my future.
空はなにもいわず　だけど私にこの道を照らしている
The sky remains silent.
Only illuminating this path before me.
透き通る景色を感じて
Feel the translucent scenery.
旋律を夕陽が奏で
The setting sun plays a melody.
透き通る景色を感じて
Feel the translucent scenery.
The setting sun plays a melody.
旋律を夕陽が奏で